Guide to the Society of Medical History of Chicago Records 1830-1982
University of Chicago Library
Society of Medical History of Chicago. Records
1830-1982
Crerar Ms 33
31.5 linear feet (36 boxes)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
The Society of Medical History of Chicago was founded in 1909 "to secure and preserve matters pertaining to the history of medical institutions, organizations and individuals particularly of Chicago and the adjacent country; and to stimulate interest in medical history in general." Original members of the society's council included George H. Cleveland, Henry T. Byford, Nathan S. Davis, John Edwin Rhodes, George H. Weaver, and Ludvig Hektoen. The records of the Society of Medical History of Chicago include the organization's administrative documents, as well as its collections of historic material on the history of medicine
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Historical Note
In 1909, the Society of Medical History of Chicago was founded in "to secure and preserve matters pertaining to the history of medical institutions, organizations and individuals particularly of Chicago and the adjacent country; and to stimulate interest in medical history in general." Original members of the society's council included George H. Cleveland, Henry T. Byford, Nathan S. Davis, John Edwin Rhodes, George H. Weaver, and Ludvig Hektoen.
In its early development, the society's explicit purpose was the collection and preservation of material documenting the history of medicine in Chicago. These historical collections were built during the early 1910s through early 1920s, and included print and manuscript material, primarily related to medicine in Chicago in the mid- to late-nineteenth century.
Beginning in the mid-1930s, the society shifted the focus of its activities to publishing, public programs and social events. The organization sponsored lectures, meetings and other events, including the annual Morris Fishbein Lecture; it published the Bulletin of the Society of Medical History of Chicago and internal newsletters. Key members of the group during the mid- to late-twentieth century included Ilza Veith, Frederick Stenn, Leo M. Zimmerman, Morris Fishbein, Allen G. Debus, James B. Herrick, William A. Pusey, Arthur F. Abt, H.W. Kienast, Joseph H. Kiefer, Walter L. Necker, George H. Coleman and William K. Beatty. In 2005, the organization was renamed the Society of Medical History and Humanities of Chicago to reflect its broader research interests.
Scope Note
The records of the Society of Medical History of Chicago include the organization's administrative documents, as well as its collections of historic material on the history of medicine.
Series I: Administration, contains material related to the activities and operation of the society from 1909-1982. Material in this series includes correspondence, minutes, reports, announcements, membership lists, proceedings, newsletters and broadsides.
Series II: Historical Collections, contains materials that the society compiled for research in the history of medicine. In this series are collections of organizational records, personal papers, publications and photographs. This series is divided into subseries by type of collection or format. While the collections primarily document medicine in Chicago and Cook County in the mid- to late-nineteenth century, this series also includes material relevant to the medical history of other regions such as Indiana, New York and Philadelphia.
Related Resources
Browse finding aids by topic.
Subject Headings
Cleveland, George Henry; Davis, N.S. (Nathan Smith), 1817-1904; Debus, Allen G.; Hektoen, Ludvig, 1863-1951; Le Count, Edwin Raymond, 1868-1935; Senn, Nicholas, 1844-1908; Stenn, Frederick; Weaver, George H. (George Howitt), b. 1866-; Chicago Medical Club; Chicago Medical College; Chicago Medical Society; Cook County Hospital (Chicago, Ill.); Rush Medical College; Society of Medical History of Chicago; Great Fire, Chicago, Ill., 1871; Medical colleges -- Illinois; Medical colleges -- United States; Medical education -- United States; Medicine -- History; Medicine -- Illinois -- Chicago; Medicine -- Societies, etc.; Temperance; Physicians -- Illinois -- Chicago; Surgeons -- Illinois -- Chicago; Women doctors; Photographs; Scrapbooks
INVENTORY
- Series I: Administration
  Series I: Administration, contains material related to the operation of the society from 1909-1982, with a concentration of material from 1963-1979. Material in this series includes correspondence, minutes, reports, announcements, membership lists, proceedings, newsletters and broadsides.
  Early records of the society, including material related to its founding and preliminary organization, are found in a scrapbook dated 1909-1936. A chronological file of records collected by society officers also includes material from this same period through 1979. A file of drafts, broadsides and photocopied texts related to the history of the society is also included.
  - Scrapbook, 1909-1936 (Box 1)
  - Chronological file, 1909-1969 (Box 2, Folder 1-8)
  - Chronological file, 1969-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Drafts, broadsides and photocopied texts, 1916-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series II: Historical Collections
  This series contains materials that the society compiled for research in the history of medicine. Most of the primary materials in this series date from the 1860s-1890s. While the collections mainly document the history of medicine in Chicago and Cook County, this series also includes material relevant to the medical history of Indiana, New York, Philadelphia, and other regions. The society's correspondence and notes about the provenance and acquisition of collections are sometimes included with the primary materials.
  This series is divided into subseries by type of collection or format.
  Subseries 1: Organizational Records, is arranged alphabetically by organization. This subseries includes administrative records, course material and publications. Represented are Chicago-area hospitals, universities and colleges, private clubs and societies, businesses and committees. Notable in this subseries are records of Cook County Hospital, Rush Medical College, the Chicago Medical Club, and the Medical Relief Committee, which was organized to support medical professionals following the 1871 Chicago Fire. Oversize material, including important records of the Cook County Hospital and the Chicago Retreat for the Insane, has been transferred to Subseries 6.
  Subseries 2: Biographical Files, is arranged alphabetically by name. This subseries consists of material collected by F.D. DuSouchet from 1911-1913, documenting the biographies of doctors active in Chicago in the mid- to late-nineteenth century. Most of the material in this subseries is correspondence between DuSouchet and the family members of individual doctors. Also included are photographs, biographical sketches, memorial material and clippings. General files contain lists of names, unidentified and partially identified material, and unanswered letters. Related papers of DuSouchet are included in Subseries 3. This subseries is also related to the portrait collection developed by DuSouchet, and included in Subseries 5.
  Subseries 3: Personal Papers, is also arranged alphabetically. This subseries includes correspondence, manuscripts, personal business records, course material and publications. Most of the individuals represented were physicians or medical students in the Chicago area in the mid- to late-nineteenth century; also included are papers of George Weaver and others involved in the organization of the Society of Medical History of Chicago. Many of the individual collections in this subseries are very small and consist of only a few items. Substantial collections in this subseries include the correspondence of George H. Cleveland; a collection of a variety of personal papers of Edwin R. LeCount; historical research compiled by George C. Weaver; and notes taken by James W. Walker in courses taught by prominent faculty at Chicago Medical College. Oversize
  material, including a letterbook of correspondence of Nicholas Senn, and notes taken by Ludvig Hektoen on Senn's lectures, has been transferred to Subseries 6.
  Subseries 4: Publications, contains reprints, periodicals, pamphlets and books. Included are works on medical history, medicine, dentistry, temperance, nutrition and public health. Material in this series is arranged alphabetically by title or author; general collections of reprints, periodicals and pamphlets are found at the end of the subseries. An incomplete run of the Bulletin of the Society of Medical History of Chicago is also included. Many of these materials were collected by Nathan S. Davis, who served as president of the American Medical Temperance Association.
  Subseries 5: Prints and Photographs, contains primarily black and white photographic prints, with a small number of engravings and reproductions from publications. Included in this subseries are photographs from the collection of Dr. Samuel Slaymaker, taken mainly at Rush Medical College and Cook County Hospital during the 1880s. Also included is a collection of portraits of prominent physicians and other medical professionals, organized alphabetically by subject. Biographical summaries are included with some of the portraits. Oversize material from this subseries, including additional photographs from Slaymaker's collection, have been transferred to Subseries 6.
  Subseries 6: Oversize Materials, contains items transferred from previous subseries, as well as a framed print and a pair of Perkins's tractors mounted for display. Significant material in this subseries includes a casebook for the Chicago Home for the Insane; record books documenting autopsies and obstetric cases at Cook County Hospital; notes on lectures of Nicholas Senn taken by Ludvig Hektoen; a letterbook of correspondence with Senn; and photographs from the collection of Samuel Slaymaker.
  - Subseries 1: Organizational Records
    - Chicago Medical Club, 25th anniversary publication, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Chicago Medical Club, correspondence and organizational history, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chicago Medical College and Northwestern University Medical School, announcements, circulars and lists of alumni, 1867-1912 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Chicago Medical Society, proceedings, 1888-1889 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - College of Physicians and Surgeons, lecture tickets, 1834-1835 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Cook County Hospital, rules and regulations booklets and directories, 1868-1910 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Cook County Hospital Alumni Association, minutes, announcements, directories and constitutions, 1884-1926 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Cook County Hospital, Illinois Training School for Nurses pamphlet, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Gale and Blocki Prescription Druggists, prescriptions, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Gale and Blocki Prescription Druggists, prescriptions, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Illinois State Board of Health, graduate certificates, 1877-1878 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Insomnia Club, handbook, 1891 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Medical Relief Committee, record book, 1871; correspondence, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Medical Relief Committee, receipts, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Medical Relief Committee, minutes, correspondence and clippings, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Medical Relief Committee, correspondence and statements of losses in fire, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Physicians' Club of Chicago, handbook, 1895 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Rush Medical College, lecture tickets, 1834-1874 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
    - Rush Medical College, commencement addresses and valedictory speeches, 1861-1862 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Rush Medical College, announcements, 1862-1900 (Box 6, Folder 5-7)
    - Rush Medical College, announcements, 1902-1911 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Rush Medical College, spring course faculty meeting minutes, 1869-1871 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Rush Medical College, unidentified lecture notes, 1875-1876 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Rush Medical College, triennial catalogue, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Rush Medical College, faculty and alumni address book (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Rush Medical College Alumni Association, proceedings, 1879-1884 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Therapeutic Club, programs and memorial publications, 1895-1898 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2: Biographical Files
    - Addison, Robert Stout (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Allen, J. Adams (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Amerman, George K. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Andrews, Edmund (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Anthony, Henry Giles (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Armor, Samuel Glasgow (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Avery, Samuel J. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - B, general (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Baccus, Victor (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Bachellé, C.V. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Ballard, Charles Nelson (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Banks, James N. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Bartholdy, N.C. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Bartlett, John (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Bartlett, Rufus H. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Baxter, Andrew James (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Beardsley, Hiram Hoyt (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Beardsley, L.S. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Bell, Horace R. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Benson, John Alfred (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Benson, Joseph Wesley (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Bert, Eddy (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Beseler, Joseph (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Best, John Ellis (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Bettman, Boerne (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Betts, Josiah Thatcher (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Blake, Samuel Coleman (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Bird, J. Herman (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Blaney, James van Zant (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Bluthardt, Theodore J. (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Boening, Louis (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Bond, Thomas S. (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Bogart, Henry Vander (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Bogue, Robert Griswold (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Boone, Levi D. (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Boyer, Valentine A. (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Brauns, Philo (Box 8, Folder 37-38)
    - Breidenstein, Frederick L. (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Brinkerhoff, John (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Brooks, Almon (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Brooks, J.W. (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Brower, Daniel Roberts (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Bruce, J.P. (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Butterfield, William (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Byford, William Heath (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - C, general (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Carpenter, George B. (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Carpenter, Philo (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Carr, Ezra S. (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Carr, Watson (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Cerf, Jacob (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Cheney, Lucian P. (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Christopher, Walter S. (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Clark, Charles Merrill (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Clarke, John Spangler (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Clarke, Harry (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Clarke, Henry (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Clarke, William Edwin (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Clendening, John Wesley (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Coatsworth, George (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Collins, Arthur M. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Collins, James Alexander (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Conradi, Julius (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Corbus, Joseph Rickets (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Creighton, Charles J. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Cronin, Henry Philip (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - D, general (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Dass (Dundas), Johan Christian (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Davis, Nathan Smith (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Davisson, Alfred W. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Deering, Thomas W. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Deming, Henry H. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - DeVeny, Stephen Charles (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - DeVille, Titus (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Dewey, Frank (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - DeWolf, Oscar C. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Dexter, Ransom (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Dickerman, Edward T. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Dietrich, Henry (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Dodge, David (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Downey, William Stewart (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Dubs, Rudolph S. (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Duck, Charles H. (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Dyas, George Keating (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Earle, Charles Warrington (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Egan, Egan, Charles B. Egan, William B. (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Eggert, F.C. (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Eldredge, John W. (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Emmons, Francis A. (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Etheridge, James Henry (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Evans, John (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - F, general (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Falls, Samuel Kemp (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - Favill, Henry Baird (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - Fenger, Christian (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - Ferguson, Alexander Hugh (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Fessel, Christian Gottlob (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - Finley, Clement Alexander (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - Fisher, Alexander (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Fitch, Graham N. (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Fitch, Thomas Davis (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Fleming, John McLean (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Flint, Austin (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - Fonda, David B. (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Foster, Addison H. (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Foster, John H. (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Freer, Joseph Warren (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Gaetjens, Heinrich Otto (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - Garrett, Erasmus (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Geiger, Henry (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Goodhue, Josiah C. (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Gore, Joel Rogers (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Gradle, Henry (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Greene, F.C. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Griswold, William P. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Groesbeck, Abram (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - H, general (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Hahn, Hahn, Henry H. Hahn, James Augustus (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Hale, Edwin M. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Hall, H. Newberry (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Hall, Randolph Nathaniel (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Hallberg, C.S.N. (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Hamill, Robert C. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Hatch, Ira (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
    - Hatheway, Otis Pope (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Hatfield, Marcus Patten (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Haven, Samuel Rush (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Haven, Simon Z. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Hayes, Justin (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Hayes, Plymmon S. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Helmuth, Carl Albert (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Hempstead, Charles Wilt (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Henrotin, Joseph Fortunat (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Hequembourg, Julien E. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Herrick, William B. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Hessert, Gustav (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Heydock, Mills O. (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Hiatt, Alfred Hadley (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Hildreth, Joseph S. (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Hoadley, Albert Edward (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Hoffman, Theodor (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Holroyd, Eugene Ernest (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Horsey, Edward H. (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Hosmer, Arthur B. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Huber, H.S. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Hunt, Florence Winifred (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Hunt, William Carlton (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Hunter, Warren (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Hurlbut, Horatio (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Hurlbut, Vincent (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Hutchins, John W. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Hutchinson, James Marion (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Ingals, E. Fletcher (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Isham, Ralph W. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Jackson, Abraham Reeves (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Jacobsen, Sigismund Daniel (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Jaggard, William Wright (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Jay, Milton (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Jewell, James Stewart (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Hosmer Allen (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Jones, Hugh Webster (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Jones, Robert W. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Jones, Samuel L. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Kimberly, Edmund Stoughton (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Klebs, E. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Knapp, M.L. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Krusemarck, William (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Kurtz, Carl E. (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - L, general (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Landis, Edmund M. (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Larsen, Peter Clausen (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Lee, Edward W. (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Little, William (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Locke, Robert Douthitt (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Ludlow, Ruben (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Luken, Martin H. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Lynn, Isaiah Pierce (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - M, general (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Macalister, John (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Major, Laban Shipp (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Manierre, Charles Edward (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Mannheimer, Michael (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Marguerat, Eugene (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Mather, Martin (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Maxwell, Philip (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - McArthur, A.L. (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - McArthur, Erial (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - McClure, Vincent Carpenter (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - McDermott, Joseph (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - McIlwain, Matthew (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - McLean, John (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - McLernan, Alexander Stuart (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - McVickar, Brookholst (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Meacham, Silas (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Mercer, Frederick W. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Mergher, Marie J. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Merrill, Julia Dyer (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Merriman, Henry Payson (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Meyer, Max (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Millard, S.R. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Miller, Benjamin Coke (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Truman Washington (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Mohr, John (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Montgomery, Frank H. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Norcom, Frederick B. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - O'Malley, T.F. (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Oswald, Julius William (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Otto, Joseph (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Paddock, Solomon Allen (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Palmer, A.B. (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Paoli, Gerhard C. (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Park, Roswell (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Parkes, Charles J. (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Pearson, Nels Peter (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Priestman, John (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Purdy, Charles Wesley (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Quinlan, Charles H. (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Rauch, John H. (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Ray, Charles H. (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Reid, John (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Rimpert, George (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Robinson, Byron (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Robinsin, William Francis (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Rohr, Frederick William (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Rogers, E.C. (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Roler, Edward Oscar Fitzalan (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Root, Dan S. (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Rosenthal, Jacob (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Ross, Joseph P. (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Rutter, Charles Lindley (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Rutter, David (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - S, general (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Saur, Louis (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Scammon, Franklin (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Schaeffer, Frederick C. (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Schaller, John (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - Scheppers, D.Q. (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Schloetzer, George (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Seeley, Thaddeus Pomeroy (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Seiffert, Rudolph (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Sherman, J.S. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Shipman, George E. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Shumway, Charles W. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Silva, C.C.P. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Skeer, John Dugan (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Skelton, Leonard (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Small, A.R. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Smith, David S. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Smith, John Mark (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Smith, Orrin (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Smith, William C. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Soden, William Hill (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Spafford, Horatio G. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Spencer, Thomas Rush (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Starkweather, Ralph E. (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Starr, John F. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Steele, Ezra A. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Stehman, Henry B. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Storck, Charles (Box 13, Folder 21)